我们走运了
We are so in luck!
房东说这些好东西都可以给我们
Treeger said we could have all this cool stuff!
等一下
Wait right there.
不行  我要划走了
Oh, no. i'm paddling away.
真的  这些生锈的垃圾都不要钱
Really? we got all this rusty crap for free?
还有一堆泡泡棉
This and a bunch of bubble wrap.
有些完全没挤过
And, some of it is not even popped!
我们真是白人垃圾
Could we be more white trash?
我真是绝望透了
How desperate am I?
还好钱德勒不在  谁也惨不过他
Oh! Good thing Chandler's not here, he always wins at this game.
我刚答应帮我妈的宴会办外烩
I just told my Mom I'd cater a party for her.
-为什么  -因为我需要钱
-how come? -i need the money.
而且这样正好可以抛开
and I thought that it'd be a great way to get rid of
最后一丝自尊
that last little schmidgen of self-respect.
别这样  这是好事
Come on, I think this is a good thing.
要不是觉得你行  妈不会找你
I don't think Mom would've hired you if she didn't think you were good at what you do.
你不必拍她马屁  她又听不到
You don't have to stick up for her. She can't here you.
有果汁没
Hey! Umm, do you guys have any juice?
只有腌黄瓜汁
Just pickle.
瑞秋  说来好笑
Hey uh, Rach, Funny story.
我昨天在路上遇见乔安娜
i bumped into joanna yesterday.
我的上司乔安娜  一定很尴尬
My boss, Joanna? Wow, that must've been awkward.
事实上她找我一起去喝酒
Well, no, actually she uh, asked me if I wanted to get a drink.
你没有答应  是吧
You ah, you didn't say 'Yes' to that did you?
早  瑞秋
Hello, Rachel.
一开始没答应
Well, not at first.
她在这里干什么
What is she doing here?
我不懂  你上次跟她约会说她很无聊
I don't understand! Last time you went out with her you said she was a dud!
我太快下定论了  这次我们
Well, I think I judged her too quickly, and this time we were able
可以进展到下一个阶段
we were able to take the relationship to the next level.
我上次差点被炒鱿鱼
Well, last time I almost got fired.
你要做个了结
You must end it, you must end it now!
这可不是每天都有的事
Oh, come on! It's not like this is an everyday occurrence for me!
通常我都一个人睡
I mean usually I'm pretty much just in there by myself.
钱德勒
Chandler!!
答应我  会做个了结
Promise me, you will end it.
-好  我答应  -谢谢你
-i promise. i'll end it. -thank you.
你知道  我的牺牲很大
I hope you know what I'm giving up for ya,
她可不仅只是你的上司
because she's not just the boss in your office,
你懂吧
if you know what I mean.
对不起  我懂
Oh-oh, sorry, I-I knew what he meant.
外烩大厨忙得怎样
How's the hired help?
很顺利  乳酪火腿馅饼快好了
Doing great, the quiches are coming along.
这是什么  蓝色指甲油
What's this? Blue nail polish?
对  我觉得很好看
Yeah, I thought it was cute.
你奶奶死后指甲就是这个颜色
Ahh, that's what your Grandmother's hands looked like when we found her.
我问你一个问题
Let me ask you a question.
你为什么找我
Why did you hire me?
理查一直说他的派对餐点很棒
Oh, well Richard raved about the food at his party,
但你当时在跟他上床
of course you were sleeping with him.
后来我听说  那场同志婚礼的菜很好
Then I heard the food at that lesbian wedding was very nice,
你应该没跟那些人上床
I assume you weren't sleeping with anybody there.
至少你有点厨艺
Though, at least that would be something.
天哪  你听到了
Oh my God! Did you hear that?
她是觉得我很行才找我
She hired me because she thinks I'm good.
我没听到这个
Okay, I didn't hear that.
她不是在可怜我
Oh yeah, she didn't hire me out of pity,
不是想在朋友面前刁我
it wasn't so she could pick on me in front of her friends,
是真的觉得我行
she actually thinks I'm good.
还有  如果你是同志就太酷了
Wow! And hey, it's cool if you're a lesbian!
午安  你是这里的家长吗
Good afternoon, are you the decision maker of the house?
你目前拥有一套百科全书
Do you ah, currently own a set of encyclopedias?
没有  不过分类广告上
No! No. But ah, try the classifieds,
什么都有
people sell everything in there.
我不是要买  我是要卖
Actually, I'm not buying.I'm selling.
问你一个问题
Let me ask you one question.
你是否曾在朋友们聊天时
Do your friends ever have a conversation...
而你只能跟着点头
...and you just nod along,
却搞不懂他们在说什么
even though you're not really sure what they're talking about?
告诉你  这根本是违宪
I'm telling you it's totally unconstituional.
没错
Oh yeah, I totally agree.
我觉得他应该得诺贝尔奖
I think he deserves a Nobel Prize.
才不是
Nooo!!
很像阿尔冈京族小孩的桌子
It was like the algonquin kids' table.
抱歉  对不起
Excuse me. i'm sorry.
你发呆已经2分半钟
You haven't said anything for about two minutes.
你到底有没有兴趣
Are you at all interested?
有请进
Come on in.
-怪了  -什么
-that's weird. -what?
你的假指甲
Your nails.
我知道  我从没戴过
Oh, I know, I never wear fake ones. I just did it
我怕咬指甲被我妈念
so my Mom wouldn't give me grief about me biting them.
我是说你现在只有九个指甲
Oh, no, I meant that it's weird that you only have nine now.
天哪
Oh, my god!
等一下
Wait a minute.
我之前要烤
I had them when i put
天哪  在馅饼里面
Oh, my god! it's in the quiche!
-天哪  -别着急
-oh, my god! -okay, don't panic.
我现在去店里帮你买一组新指甲
I'm gonna go to the store,I'm gonna get you another set of nails,
没有人会知道  你还是很美
No one will know, and you'll look great!
你是怕他们会吃到
Oh! Oh, it's 'cause they're gonna eat? That's the problem.
女儿  别咬指甲
Honey, don't bite your nails.
你先别发飙
Okay ah, please don't freak out.
不过某个馅饼里有一片假指甲
Umm, but ah, there's a blue fingernail in one of the quiche cups,
而且无从找起
and there's no way to know which one.
找到的人可以中大奖
And! Whoever finds it wins the prize!
我不会发飙
I'm not freaking out.
-那你笑什么  -没事  你爸输我5块钱
-why are you laughing? -It's nothing, it's just now your father owes me $5.
你赌我会掉指甲
What? You bet I'd lose a nail?
别傻了  我只是赌我会用上这个
Oh no, don't be silly. I just bet I'd need these.
冷冻千层面
Frozen lasagnas?
你赌我会搞砸
You bet that I'd screw up?!
你还说什么我很行
So all that stuff about hiring me because I was good was...
不  那都是真的
No-no-no, that was all true.
只是怕你把自己推翻了
This was just in case you pulled a Monica.
你答应过心理医生不再这么说
You promised Dr. Weinburg, you'd never use that phrase.
拜托  有点幽默感
Oh honey, come on, have a sense of humour,
你总是不懂得自嘲
you've never been able to laugh at yourself.
是啊
That's right.
我妈对我没信心  好好笑
My Mom doesn't have any faith in me! Oh, that's hilarious! Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha.
哪里好笑
I don't get it.
不  我对你有信心
No, I have faith...
不  你有的是千层面
No! You have lasagnas!
毁掉的馅饼好了
Op, the ruined quiches are ready.
我们不该  这不像分手
It just doesn't...feel like we're breaking up.
是分手  我好伤心
No, we are. I'm sad.
可以等到明天
Uh, can't you wait until tomorrow? all right
太不可思议了
Unbelievable!!
谢谢
Thanks.
不是  我得去见我的老板
No, no, that was my boss. I have to go.
你干什么
What are you doing?
-穿衣服  -为啥
-i'm getting dressed. -why?
光着屁股走在路上会被扔东西
When I walk outside naked people throw garbage at me.
等一下  给你看个东西
Wait. I wanna show you something.
什么东西
What is it?
别人送的一个小道具
Just a little gag gift somebody gave me.
把手合在一起
Put your hands together.
你又不是我的老板
You're not the boss of me.
你是
Yeah, you are.
好辣
Saucy!
我马上回来
I'll be back in two minutes.
你要这样把我挂着
You are, you're gonna leave me like this?
知道你在等我
Knowing you're here, waiting for me
很令人兴奋
I think it's kinda exciting.
好  但要是你不马上回来
Okay. But if you don't come back soon,
我也不能怎么样
there's pretty much nothing I can do about it!
我帮你带了马克龙回来
Hi! I brought you back a macaroon!
很好  热脸贴到我的冷屁股了
Oh great! I'll keep it in my butt with your nose.
奇怪  她把门锁上了
That's weird, she locked the door.
你知道为什么  里面有圣诞奖金名单
Y'know why? She's got the Christmas bonus list in there.
我早上看到她在打
I saw her working on it this morning.
你可别说出去
Okay, swear you won't tell,
马克离职时给了我一把钥匙
but when Mark left he gave me a key to Joanna's office.
你想看名单
You wanna see the list?
你好吗
How are you?
乔安娜  办公室
Hello, Joanna......'s office.
对不起  我还要一阵子
I'm really sorry but I may be a little while longer.
-多久  -几小时
-How little?! -a couple hours. I feel awful.
一点也不好玩  马上给我回来
Look, this isn't funny! You get back here right now!
-不行  -为啥
-I can't!! -why not?
我在我老板的车上
I'm in my boss's car!
-什么  -到隧道了
-What?! -tunnel!
怎样
What?
瑞秋  你进来一下
Rachel, could i see you for a moment?
好  现在是这样
Okay, here's the situation.
手铐的钥匙挂在门上
The keys to the cuffs are on the back of the door.
你能不能行行好
Could you be a doll and
拿了钥匙  冲过来  帮我解锁
...and grab them and scoot on over here and unlock me?
题外话  好漂亮的套装
And on a totally separate subject, that's a lovely pantsuit.
你答应要跟她分手的
You promised you would break up with her.
我是跟她分手
I did break up with her! she just
只不过她真的很狂野
She just took it really, really well!
你都没想过  这样会破坏我的事业
And the fact that you were Jeopardizing my career never entered your mind?
我想过
It did enter my mind!
但后来的事让这个念头飞了
But then something happened that made it, shoot right out.
你害自己被铐住  就自己想办法脱困
Y'know what Chandler, you got yourself into those cuffs, you get yourself out of them.
不  我没办法
No-no-no-no-no-no-no!! I can't get myself right out of them!
你把我跟脱逃大师钱德勒搞混了
You must have me confused with the Amazing Chandler!!
帮帮我  她可能要去很久
Unlock me! she could be gone for hours,
我好冷  而且
and i'm cold and....
钱德勒  好  够了
Oh, Chandler!! All right! this is it!
不准你再见她
You never see Joanna again!
永远
Never!
-不准再进这个办公室  -好的
-You never come into this office again! -Fine
把随身听还给我
You give me back my Walkman!
我没借过
I ... never borrowed your Walkman.
那就是我弄丢了  买一台给我
Well, then I lost it. You buy me one!
没问题  快解开  太好了
You got it! Here we go! Come on! This is great!
会痛
Does it hurt?
我只是看别人都会哀一声
No, i always see guys do this when handcuffs are taken off.
亲爱的裤子
Hello, sweet pants!
慢着  你要怎么跟乔安娜说
Wait! what will you tell joanna?
说什么
About what?
她看你走了  会知道是我放的
When she sees that you're gone,she's gonna know that I let you out,
我会被解雇
and that I was in here, and I'm gonna get fired!
我会撒谎  我最会撒谎了
I'll make something up! I'm good at lying,
我的确借了你的随身听
I actually did borrow your Walkman!
行不通的  她会知道我有钥匙
No, there's nothing to make up, She'll know i have a key to her office.
我得把你铐回去
I've got to get you locked up back the way you were!
想都别想
I don't think so.
真是好太多了
Well, this is much better.
看着  有朋友有如下兴趣
So, here's somebody interesting,
乔伊  你对梵谷认识多少
Joey. What do you know about Van Gogh?
-他割掉自己的耳朵  -还有呢
-he cut off his ear. -and?
没了
I'm out.
他画了这个
He painted that.
不错
Wow! That's pretty nice.
我以为他是罚自己画不好
I thought he cut off his ear 'cause he sucked.
-还有什么  -来看看
-What else you got in there? -let's see....
-教皇住在哪里  -森林里
-where does the pope live? -ln the woods.
等等  那是开玩笑的
No wait-wait, that's the joke answer.
他住在梵蒂冈
Actually its, Vatican City.
你知道什么是硫化橡胶
Now ahh, what do you know about vulcanised rubber?
节育用品
Spock's birth control.
你需要这套书
You need these books.
这里是你的旧房间
This used to be your room?
你小时候一定很健美
Wow! You must've been in really good shape as a kid
我真是个白痴
Ohh, I'm such an idiot.
我居然以为她会改变
I can't believe I actually thought she could change.
谁管你娘怎么想
Well, who cares what your Mom thinks?
你把自己推翻了
So you "pulled a monica."
这句话还真流行
Oh good, I'm glad that's catching on.
谁说这一定要是坏话
No but, why does that have to be a bad thing.
去改变它的意义
Just change what it means. Y'know?
证明你妈是错的
Go down there and prove your Mother wrong.
你把工作顺利完成
Finish the job you were hired to do,
我们管它叫  推翻莫妮卡
and we'll call that pulling a Monica.
什么
What?
小孩每一科都拿A
Okay, umm, if a kid gets straight A's,
父母会说  你推翻了莫妮卡
his parents would say, "Yeah, he pulled a Monica."
消防员救出一个宝宝
Y'know? Or a fireman saves a baby,
大家说  你推翻了莫妮卡
and they go, "Yeah I know, he pulled a Monica."
有人打全垒打  播报员会说
Someone hits a homer, and they
这是一支红不让
"Yeah, that one's outta here."
有些事是不能变的
Though some things don't change.
好了  我要下楼去
All right, I'll go down there.
我不上千层面  我要上我做的菜
But, I'm not gonna serve the lasagna. I'm gonna serve something I make.
我的咪咪真有力
Wow! My breasts are really strong.
钱德勒  拜托  我得把你铐回去
Chandler! Chandler, please, I have to get you locked back the way you were,
我的饭碗快不保了
I am sooo gonna lose my job,
她很在意办公室的隐私权
she's very private about her office.
我总算知道原因了
Now I know why.
你不管怎样都有麻烦
Hey, look, you're in trouble either way! Okay?
如果她回来了  看见我被铐在柜子上
If she comes back and sees me locked to this instead of the chair,
就会知道你进来过  所以你还不如让我走
she's gonna know you were in here. So you might as well just let me go.
我帮你洗浴室1个月
What if I clean your bathroom for a month?
还是洗不干净
It still wouldn't be clean.
我只要自由
All I want is my freedom.
-揉脚1个月 - 自由
-Foot rubs for a month! -Freedom!
把你的相片通通整理好
I'll take all of your photos and put them into photo albums!
自由  自由
i want my freedom!
你为什么不听  苏菲  救救我
Why won't you hear me! sophie, help me!
苏菲  坐下
Sophie, sit!
请你冷静  好吗
No! God, would you just calm down!
我再说最后一次
I'm gonna say this for the last time.
能不能请你
Would you please just...
我对呕吐的了解还真少
Wow! There's a lot I didn't know about vomit.
等一下
In a minute.
你觉得如何  乔伊
So, what do you say, Joey?
1200元拥有整套百科全书
You get the whole set of encyclopedias for twelve hundred dollars,
平均一本才50元
that works out to just 50 bucks a book!
你觉得我有1200吗
You think I have $1200?
我大白天窝在家里
I'm home in the middle of the day,
还用凉椅洋伞当家具
and I got patio furniture in my living room.
有些事是书上学不到的
I guess there's a few things you don't get from book learnin'.
你能凑出多少
Well ah, what can you swing?
0头期款  长期月付0元
How about zero down and zero a month for a long, long time?
你什么都没有
You don't have, anything?
你想看我有什么
You wanna see what I got?
我有一个巧克力棒
I've got a baby Tootsie Roll,
一张电影票根  钥匙  纸巾
a movie stub, keys, a kleenex...
一块小石头
a rock,
和一个玩具兵
and an army man.
好  我懂了  耽误你了
Okay, I-I get the picture. Uh, thanks, for your time.
和一张50元
And a 50.
这一定是钱德勒的裤子
Huh, these must be Chandler's pants.
50元可以买一本
For 50 bucks, you can get one book!
要哪一本  A  B  C
What will it be? A? B? C?
我还是买V好了
Oh, I-I think I'm gonna stick with the V,
我想看看结局如何
I wanna see how this bad boy turns out.
-我帮你买和包圣诞礼物  -不要
-I ah, will buy and wrap all of your Christmas gifts. -No!
我每天早上帮你榨柳橙汁
I'll squeeze you fresh orange juice every morning!
-有果肉吗  -是的
-With extra pulp? -yeah.
不要
No!
我知道了
I've got it!
你才不知道
You don't have it.
我完全知道了
I have so got it.
这件事会传出去  挡也挡不住
There's gonna be rumours about this, there's no way to stop it.
苏菲知道  莫妮卡  菲比知道
Sophie knows, Monica and Phoebe know.
-她们怎么会知道  -我说的
-How do Monica and Phoebe know? -i called them.
当她们问我看到什么
when they ask me what I saw,
我可以很大方
...i can be very generous...
也可以很小气
...or very stingy.
说下去
Go on.
我可以让你成为传奇
I can make you a legend.
我可以让你成为现代唐璜
I can make you this generation's Milton Berle.
-而唐璜  -根本比不上你
-And Milton Berle has a... -not compared to you.
怎样  客人碰都没碰千层面
Well? They're not even touching the lasagna!
-真的  -他们好喜欢你的砂锅
-Really?! -They love your casserole!
真不敢相信  这刚才还都只是材料
It's hard to believe a while ago this was just ingredients.
大家都很喜欢你做的菜
Everyone seems to like your dish.
那你呢
And you?
我觉得
I thought it was...
很好吃
...quite tasty.
要是大家都喜欢  你也喜欢
So if everyone liked it, and you liked it,
那就代表很成功  而你
that would make this a success. which would make you....
贱人
A bitch?
我想说的是错误  但你的措辞也不错
I meant "wrong," but we can use your word.
好吧  我错了
Well I was wrong.
不得不说
And i have to say...
你让我大开眼界
...you really impressed me today.
你还可以说她推翻了莫妮卡
You might even say that she "pulled a monica."
她不知道我们改过了
She doesn't know we switched it.
下次你帮我办外烩
And the next time you cater for me...
冷冻库里只会有冰
...there will be nothing but ice in the freezer.
这是很大的鼓励
That really means a lot.
妈  别咬指甲
Mom, don't bite your nails!
钱德勒你好
Hello, Chandler.
我爱你
I love you.
怎么回事
Wh-what's going on?
少来了
No he doesn't!
拖了2小时
Two hours, that lasted!
所以你跟乔安娜分手了
So did you break up with Joanna?
是的
I think so.
幸好她跟维苏威一样  爆炸之前你就闪了
Well, it's good thing you got out when you did, before she blew up like that Vesuvius.
那座火山
The volcano?
讲到火山
Yeah. And speaking of volcanoes,
那些火成岩还真暴力
man are they a violent igneous rock formation.
什么
What?!
熔岩乱喷  热灰乱飞
Oh yeah, lava spewing, hot ash,
不过有些是休火山
Of course, some are dormant.
你怎么突然聊起火山来了
Why are you talking about volcanoes all of the sudden?
不一定要聊火山
Well, we can talk about something else.
你们想聊什么  活体解剖
What do you want to talk about? Vivisection?
输精管
The Vasdeferens?
越战
The Vietnam War?
有人看那部韩战纪录片吗
Oh! Did anybody see that-that documentary on the Korean War?
韩国那么美
Oh God, Korea is such a beautiful country.
命运却好悲惨
With such a sad history.
有好多姓金的
Could there be more Kims?
-外面是谁  -是我  早安
-Who's out there? -me! good morning!
瑞秋  你能不能进来一下
Rachel, could you come in here for a moment, please?
他们没有你要的百吉饼了
Yeah, sure. Umm, they didn't have poppy seed bagels, so I...
我要了芝麻的  天啊
...so i have sesame oh, my word!
出了点办公室灾难
I seem to have had a slight office mishap.
请把门后的钥匙拿给我
Could you please get the key off the back of the door for me.
-要是可以的话  -抱歉
-lf you could. -oh, i'm sorry!
告诉你的朋友钱德勒
You can tell your friend chandler
我们这次绝对是分手了
that we're definately broken up this time.